<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maker on rahul thakoor</title>
    <link>https://rahul-thakoor.github.io/tags/maker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Maker on rahul thakoor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>rahul.thakoor@gmail.com (Rahul Thakoor)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>rahul.thakoor@gmail.com (Rahul Thakoor)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 08:12:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rahul-thakoor.github.io/tags/maker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Firmata On Arduino Compatible Boards</title>
      <link>https://rahul-thakoor.github.io/using-firmata-on-arduino-compatible-boards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 08:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rahul.thakoor@gmail.com (Rahul Thakoor)</author>
      <guid>https://rahul-thakoor.github.io/using-firmata-on-arduino-compatible-boards/</guid>
      <description>What is Arduino? Arduino is an open-source electronics prototyping platform. An Arduino board is development hardware consisting of a programmable microcontroller. The boards can collect information(inputs), act on the inputs(processing) and finally produce outputs. Typically, Arduino boards are programmed using the Arduino programming language through the Arduino IDE using custom firmware(sketches). Arduino exists in many forms and flavours, from the official boards such as the UNO, ArduinoBoard 101 and MEGA, to Arduino-compatible ones like the NodeMCU.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get started with NodeBots? - The hardware</title>
      <link>https://rahul-thakoor.github.io/how-to-get-started-with-nodebots---the-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 08:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rahul.thakoor@gmail.com (Rahul Thakoor)</author>
      <guid>https://rahul-thakoor.github.io/how-to-get-started-with-nodebots---the-hardware/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to starting a DIY Electronics project, one can be overwhelmed by the myriad of choices. With so many varieties out there, how to get started?
The basic components include: Processing, Input/Output, Circuits and Wiring and Power.
 Processing: the brain of the project, typically development boards which enable us to run our program logic.
 Inputs/Outputs: sensors, actuators, and other gadgets we connect to our boards to enhance our projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developers Conference 2017</title>
      <link>https://rahul-thakoor.github.io/developers-conference-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 08:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rahul.thakoor@gmail.com (Rahul Thakoor)</author>
      <guid>https://rahul-thakoor.github.io/developers-conference-2017/</guid>
      <description>The Developers Conference, organised by the MSCC, is the BIGGEST tech event in Mauritius. DevCon brought together tech enthusiasts, hobbyists, numerous user groups, prestigious companies, students, and more!!! I was privileged to present as a Microsoft Student Partner.
My team(@dishaykissoon and me), presented on NodeBots: Using Javascript for hardware programming. The idea was to use NodeBots and Javascript as an entry point to get more people interested in hardware programming and DIY projects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>